favthemes.com 2019-05-15

# Privacy - Amazing Joomla Templates - Joomla Extensions

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which FavThemes collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") on our website ("Site"). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by FavThemes.

### 1\. What kind of User related information do we collect and store (and for how long)

We collect and store User related information (personal identification information and anonymous information) from Users in a variety of ways: when the User visits our Site, creates an User account, places an order or submits a support request by e-mail.

We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us, by creating an account and submiting their explicit consent regarding our internal policies using our registration form.

We will always try to collect the minimum required information (either personal identification information or anonymous one) from our visiting Users in order to allow them to browser or Site, buy our products, download, use and update them in a technical productive manner and initiate electronic payments.

When registering an account on our Site, Users may be asked for a name and/or email address.

Before initiating an order, the User's cart history related information is stored for a short period of time on our server. This period depends on how long the User will continue to navigate our platform before closing the browser

After initiatiting an order, the User's order history related information is stored on our server.

If the User has initiated and completed a payed order, the order history realated information will be stored for a period of time that depends on our general legal or fiscal obligations (in some cases, even 10 years). If a payed User decides to delete his account, the order history related information will remain on our server linked only with the User's email address.

If the User has initiated and completed a free order, the order history related information will be stored untill the User requests its deletion, but not longer than 5 years, as this information can still be needed by the User in order to have access to his product's updates.

For anti-fraud related purposes, we may also store information related to the User's device [IP address](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address) (the IP address that was attached to the User's device when he initiated and completed the payment).

When interacting anonymously with our Site (that is, without creating a User account), we may store your browser header http headers information (the information your browser sends to our server in order to identify itslef) and your device IP address, following the standard way a server stores the interactions it has with a web client/browser. This kind of information (also known as "logs") might be used for anti-fraud or anti-hacking/craking/virus purposes and is deleted periodically by our automatic scripts. This deletion is also supervised by our system admin.

### 3\. Where is the User information stored and who has access to it

The User's name (if any), email address, cart and order history (if any) are stored on our server's database. The User's device IP address might as well be stored on our server's database (when linked to a payed order) and/or on our server's filesystem logs (for the other anonymous information your browser sends to our server).

When the User sends us an e-mail (support or commercial related), this e-mail is stored on our email server but might also be archived on our internal backup server. Depending on their purpose, these messages will be stored for a period of time that depends on our general legal or fiscal obligations (in some cases, even 10 years, for invoice related messages).

The above stored information can only be accessed by a very limited number of people (a maximum of three FavThemes trusted employees, with high technical and security training).

### 4\. What rights do you have regading the personal information stored on our server

You can always have access to see the personal information stored on our server. This operation can be done from your User's account page and you can also request a centralized file to be provided to you with the personal information stored on our server using the designated tool from your User's account page.

You can always choose to modify the personal information stored on our server (including the diffrent types of consents you selected at some point in time). This operation can be done from your User's account page or can be requested from us via [support@favthemes.com](mailto:support@favthemes.com). The order related information can only be modified in certain cases (if we agree for a discount or if you want to delete your account and order history and you haven't purchased any payed products). Otherwise, this information cannot be edited or deleted, for fiscal and anti-fraud purposes.

Still, modifying parts of the personal information (ex: canceling the acceptance of our "Terms and conditions") might lead to the impossibility of using our services.

You can always choose to delete all your personal identification information from our server. If so, you need to send a request to [support@favthemes.com](mailto:support@favthemes.com) or using the designated tool from your User's account page. Your request will be processed shortly and you will receive a status confirmation by e-mail.

You can always have access to what type of personal identification information we store on our server (and for how long) and to the way it is stored, accessed and used.

### 5\. How we use collected information

FavThemes may collect and use User personal information for the following purposes:

#### To provide and improve customer service

Information you provide allows us to process your orders and respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.

#### To personalize user experience

We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.

#### To improve our Site

We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.

#### To process payments

We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.

All PayPal transactions are subject to the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

#### To send periodic emails

We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If the User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service informations.

If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. This operation can also be done using the designated tool from the User's account page.

### 6\. How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our servers.

### 7\. Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others.

We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and our Site, such as sending out newsletters or building User related statistics.

We currently use the following third party service providers:

#### fonts.googleapis.com

#### www.google-analytics.com

#### maxcdn.bootstrapcdn.com/font-awesome

#### sendmachine.com

### 8\. Changes to this privacy policy

FavThemes can update this privacy policy at any time. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for changes. You acknowledge and agreed that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of any future modifications.

### 9\. Your acceptance of these terms

These terms can only be accepted by explicit consent. This explicit consent is given when creating an User account and selecting the appropiate consent related options from the registration form.

In the absence of this consent, no personal information will be collected and stored on our server, except for the anonymous related ones stated above.

### 10\. Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site or your dealings with this site, please contact us at [support@favthemes.com](mailto:support@favthemes.com).

VERSION 2.0 - Modified 18-06-2018
